你们好
Hi, there.
今晚由我为你们服务
I'll be your server for tonight.
我叫布莱恩 有任何需要尽管叫我
My name is Brian if you guys need anything.
如果我们没有任何需要该叫你什么
What's your name if we don't need anything?
帕特丽夏
Patricia.
反应很快嘛 帕特丽夏
You're quick, Patricia!
谢谢 我们今晚的特别鸡尾酒是
Thanks. So, our specialty cocktail for tonight
罗勒莫吉托
is a basil-infused mojito.
不错 我们要三杯
Oh, yum! We'll take three.
不用了 没关系 我不想喝酒
Uh, no. That's okay. I'm good.
拜托 跟我们一起在这特别的夜晚
Come on, now. Join us for a specialty cocktail
-喝杯特别的鸡尾酒吧 -就是
- on our specialty evening. - Yeah.
-请给我们三杯 -好的
- Three, please. - Okay.
你不喝的话 会有人喝的
If you don't drink it, someone will.
那个布莱恩真是个帅哥 是吧
Well, that Brian sure is a cutie, huh?
我真想要那两片嘴唇 我是说在我身上
I'd kill to have those lips. I mean on me.
我是说想要他的嘴唇在我嘴上
I mean I want his lips on my mouth.
我们能直接切入正题吗
Uh, can we just cut to the chase?
他的嘴唇很性感
He's got great lips.
不不不 我们在这里干什么
No, no, no, no, no. What are we doing here?
你们有什么目的
What is this about?
没什么 我们就是想跟我们的女儿
Nothing! We just wanted to have a fun night out
出来放松一下
with our daughter.
是啊 就把我们当做你的朋友
Yeah! Just think of us as your friends.
-是啊 -我可没有45岁的朋友
- Yeah! - I don't have 45-year-old friends.
你的父母也还没45岁呢 亲爱的
Well, you don't have 45-year-old parents yet, either, honey,
别激动
so calm down.
海莉对她的未来毫无规划
Haley has no plan for her future whatsoever.
她住在我们的地下室里
She's living in our basement,
在社区大学上课 整天混日子
taking community-college classes, and, well, meandering.
所以我们打算带她出去 放松一下
So we're gonna take her out. We'll have some fun.
让她放松警惕
And then gently ease her
跟我们友好地聊聊她的未来
into a friendly conversationabout her future.
跟我们过去采取的方式截然不同
As opposed to the approach that we've taken in the past.
你打算以后就干这个吗
Is this what you're gonna do with your life --
睡懒觉 然后自拍
Sleep late and take a selfie?!
你为什么总是批评我
Why are you always criticizing me?!
你想这样开始新的一天吗
Is this really how you want to start the day?!
我的一天五小时前就开始了
My day started 5 hours ago.
我的压力很大
I am under a lot of pressure!
怎么大 如何大 你一周只有三节课
How?! How?! You take three classes a week,
还逃了一半
and you miss half of them!
车很难停
The parking is tricky!
早上好 宝贝 我给你留了些午餐
Morning, sunshine. I saved you some lunch.
我知道了 好吗 我是很懒 天呐
I get it, okay?! I'm lazy! God!
你知道我最烦什么吗
You know what drives me crazy?
晚餐期间接到询问客户满意度的电话
Getting these customer-satisfaction calls during dinner.
他们给车换了油而已
They change the oil on your car,
却期待着我写感谢信
they want a love letter!
没错 我还在等我的医生打来电话
I know. I'm waiting for a call from my doctor's office --
"请评价您的前列腺检查
"Please rate your prostate exam.
您满意吗"
Would you say you were satisfied?"
我希望你没有
I hope you weren't.
"我希望你没有"
"I hope you weren't."
这太好笑了 歌洛莉亚
That's a good one, Gloria!
你知道用第二语言
Do you know how hard it is
幽默一下有多困难吗 杰
to be funny in a second language, Jay?
这位美丽的小姐真不错
Esta Hermosa Dama es muy buena.
达琳 你在学西班牙语吗
Ay, Darlene, you're learning Spanish?
是啊 小短和我开始上课了
Yes, Shorty and I have been taking classes.
-我们越说越好了 -当然
- We're getting good. - Oh, yeah.
太棒了
I es maravilloso!
你说的是"太棒了" 对吗
You said "That's wonderful," right?
我的意大利语功底帮了我
My Italian helps me.
为什么突然对西语感兴趣
Why the sudden interest in Spanish?
其实我们有件事想告诉你们
Well, actually, there's something we have to tell you,
好吧 你们看如何 我们
you know? All right. How's this? We're-
-我们要搬去哥斯达黎加啦 -是的
- We're moving to Costa Rica! - Yeah!
-什么 -什么时候
- What?! - When?
再过几周 那里的生活成本很低
In a couple of weeks. The cost of living is so low down there,
我们在海边找了个美丽的地方
you know? We found this beautiful place on the water.
还有自己的私人沙滩
It's got its own private beach.
泳衣可穿可不穿
Bathing suits are optional.
但还是鼓励穿上
But encouraged.
我会想你们的
Ay, I'm going to miss you guys.
别担心 我赌他们最多能坚持三个月
Don't worry about it. I give it three months, tops.
你讨厌沙滩 你知道那里有多潮湿吗
You hate the beach. And you know how humid it is down there?
我爱俱乐部的蒸汽房
I love the steam room at the club.
都一样的 除了我再也不用看着你
It's the same thing, except I don't have to see you
像一滩化了的冰淇淋一样摊在那里
sitting there like a pile of melted ice cream.
而你披着毛巾就像汤姆·塞立克
'cause you're Tom Selleck in a towel.
我已经准备好冒险了
I'm just ready for an adventure.
我想尝试些新事物
I want to try something new.
待在这里 偶尔交个帐单
Stick around here. Pick up a check every now and then.
你为什么总是这么消极
Why do you always have to be so negative?
我就觉得很好
I think it's great.
不 你说得对 我很抱歉
No, you're right. I'm sorry.
我就是有点吃惊 仅此而已
I'm surprised, that's all.
我们来为你们美好的生活新篇章干一杯吧
Let's toast this amazing new chapter of your lives.
敬拳头大小的蚊子
To mosquitoes the size of your fist.
难怪你的朋友们一个个都搬走了
This is why all your friends move away.
敬我们 终于有独处时间了
To us, alone at last.
我们两个今晚看起来都很帅
We both look very handsome tonight.
如果 如果你只说
You know, if you -- if you'd just said
我看起来很帅 我就会说 你也是
that I looked handsome, I would have said, "So do you."
我不敢冒险
I couldn't take that chance.
我想有个良好的开端
I wanted to get off on the right foot.
米奇尔和我急需一个
Mitchell and I desperately need
浪漫的夜晚来重燃激情
a romantic night out to reconnect.
是啊 我不
Yeah. I don't --
我不知道是不是因为筹划婚礼压力太大
I don't know if it's the stress of planning a wedding,
但我们最近的关系有点紧张
but we've been a little tense with each other lately, huh?
连我们的朋友马库斯都说我们最近很暴躁
Even our friend J'marcus said how bitchy we've been.
什么 他什么时候说过这话
What -- when did he say that?
在胡娇的派对上
Oh, at Pepper's party
那晚你穿了那条不太合适的裤子
that night you wore those pants that don't fit you anymore.
没错 而你带了一瓶大家都讨厌的酒
Oh, right. And you brought that bad wine that everybody hated.
-瞧 我们真的很需要 -真心的
- See? We really need this. - We really do.
那天胡娇说
Oh, you know, uh, Pepper said
为了我们的蛋糕试吃
that for our cake tasting,
我们得...
we needed to have --
我们说好的 不谈婚礼 不谈莉莉
Remember our rules -- no wedding talk, no Lily talk.
抱歉 好吧 你是对的
I'm sorry. No, you're right.
那么我们聊聊...
So, just gonna...
我们再听一遍招牌菜怎么样
Should we hear the specials again?
不能再让他重复第三遍了
We can't ask him a third time.
你知道我搬过去以后会做什么吗
You know what I might try when I'm down there?
冲浪
Surfing.
那看来你的遗体无法供亲友瞻仰了[死得很惨]
So it's gonna be a closed casket.
该我了
My turn.
你在说什么 我刚刚打进了3号球
What are you talking about? I just sunk the 3 ball.
然后你的杆子碰到了白色球
Then you moved the cue ball with your stick
就在你跟我讲要从南加州搬走
while you were telling me how you were gonna move away
去学冲浪的时候
from Southern California to try surfing.
我没碰白色球
I didn't touch the cue ball.
是啊我知道 但你就是碰了
Yeah, I know. But you did.
你说我是骗子吗 你
You're calling me a cheater? You?
一个打高尔夫最多数到5杆的家伙
The guy on the golf course who can't seem to count higher than 5?
我忘记杆数是因为
Maybe I can't keep track of my shots
我身边总有个家伙喋喋不休
because somebody won't stop talking.
那是因为我天生就爱
It is in my nature to comment on
对看到的奇闻异事发表评论
the bizarre and unusual things I see in the world,
比如你总是将胡乱一击称为挥杆
like that convulsion you call a golf swing.
你猜怎么着 我不打了
You know what? I'm done here.
是我不打了
No, I've done.
我不能站在这里接受你对我人品的质疑
I will not have my integrity questioned here.
我参加过海军
I was a Marine.
一同服役的伙伴有些都为国捐躯了
I served with guys who died.
那是老死的
Of old age!
你连国门都没出过
You never left the states!
你是说我没为国家效力吗
Are you saying I didn't serve my country?
哪个国家 美国还是哥斯达黎加
Which one, America or Costa Rica?
你干嘛老跟哥斯达黎加过不去
What's with you and Costa Rica?!
因为那是个糟糕的主意
It's a terrible idea!
你总是头脑发热冲动做决定
You get into things without thinking,
你需要被当头棒喝
and you need to be rescued,
就像上次你买的那辆车
like that time you bought that car
说什么可以变成一条船
that was supposed to turn into a boat!
-怎么了 -结果变成沉船
- Yeah? - It turned into a reef!
那是因为你手贱没关车门
That's 'cause you left your door cracked open!
是啊 又变成我的责任了
Yes, it was my fault.
记住我的话
Mark my words --
哥斯达黎加就是下一个
Costa Rica is another amphibicar
沉在湖底的水下汽车
at the bottom of a lake.
只不过这一次 我不会再捞你起来了
Only this time, I won't be bailing you out!
谁要你捞了
Who asked you?!
达琳 我们走
Darlene, we're going!
怎么了 为什么要走
Wha-- wha-- what do you mean, we're going?
谢谢款待 歌洛莉亚
Gracias, Gloria.
晚餐很棒
That was a lovely dinner.
你能忍受得了这个家伙实在太伟大了
And you are an incredible woman for putting up with this gringo!
-快点 -怎么回事
- Come on! - What happened?
祝你在哥斯达黎加有好运
Good luck in Costa Rica!
-谢谢你 杰 -他在说反话
- Aw, thanks, Jay. - He didn't mean it!
我知道 我只是想缓和下气氛
I know! I'm trying to defuse the tension.
-上酒了 -太棒了
- Here we go, guys. - Oh, yeah!
-再来三杯莫吉托 -好喝极了
- Three more Mojitos. - Yum!
是不是美味到爆啊
Aren't these yum?
我第一杯都没碰过
I didn't even drink the first one.
你确定吗 它总不会平白无故消失了吧
Are you sure? 'cause I don't think it drank itself.
是啊 确实不是
No, it did not.
我喝酒一点问题都没有
Look, I have no problem drinking.
说真的姐倒立着都能喝酒
I can literally do it standing on my head.
但是 首先 我不跟爸妈一起喝
But, "A," not with my parents,
其次 我得保持清醒
and plus, also, I needed to stay sharp,
因为他们显然醉翁之意不在酒
because they were obviously up to something,
而且我也没心情喝酒
and I was in no mood.
昨晚我才睡了不到10个小时
I barely got 10 hours of sleep last night.
我给你们再拿点水
So, I'll go get you guys some more water,
主菜应该马上就来了
and your food should be out in just a few minutes.
谢谢你伙计 你的服务很周到
Thanks so much, pal. We appreciate it.
他看上去真是积极进取啊 对吧
He seems like a real go-getter, huh?
因为他总是"进"厨房"取"东西吗
Oh, 'cause he goes and gets things?
我想知道他对人生有什么规划
I wonder what he wants to do with his life.
我总是很好奇别人的人生规划
I wonder that about people all the time.
我觉得这很正常
I think that's very common,
想知道其他人的志向
to wonder about other people's aspirations.
我总是这样
I do it all the time.
-是 你是这样 -好了 水来了
- Yeah, you do. - Yeah. Here we go.
布莱恩 作为一个年轻人
Hey, Brian, you're a young guy.
你在这之后想做点什么 有什么规划吗
Wha-- wha-- what do you want to do after this? What's your plan?
说实话
Uh, to be perfectly honest,
我大概会回家 看看电影 再磕点药
I'm probably gonna go home, watch a movie, and get high.
你们在考虑饭后的活动吗
You guys looking for something to do?
不 不 不
No. No. No.
我还有点存货
Oh. I mean, I think I got extra.
不用了 你真是...
No, no, that's --
他是在问你对人生的规划
I-I think he meant your plan for your life,
不是指今天晚上
not -- not just tonight.
我想当编剧
Oh. I want to be a screenwriter.
-很有理想 -真有意思
- Ambitious. - And -- and so interesting.
是不是啊 海莉
Isn't that interesting, Haley?
-当然了 -你应该跟他说说你的事
- Sure. - You should tell him what you're doing.
你是说在我们一起跟布莱恩嗑完药之后吗
Oh, you mean after we all go get high with Brian?
那是不可能的
That's not happening.
很抱歉拒绝你 我是说
I'm sorry. I meant that --
我知道你们的意思
No, I know what you meant.
布莱恩 你可以回避一下吗
Hey, Brian, could you give us a second?
好 当然
Uh, ye-- sure.
这就是你们今天带我来的原因
So this is what this whole night's about --
鸡尾酒 假装是我朋友 都是幌子
the drinks, the pretending to be my friend?
我们确实是你的朋友
We are your friend.
亲爱的 我们很关心你
Honey, we care about you.
我们想确定你有自己的人生规划
And we want to make sure that you -- you've got a plan,
因为看上去你在混日子
'cause it seems like you're meandering.
别这样 亲爱的 不要每次谈到
No. Sweetie, don't just start texting
你不喜欢的话题就开始玩手机
because you don't like the conversation.
-看 -这是什么
- Here. - What is this?
这是我一直在写的博客
That's a blog that I've been doing.
我真的很喜欢我拍的照片
I'm really liking my photography,
别人也总说他们喜欢我的穿衣风格
and people always say that they like the way that I dress,
所以我就在这个网站上传我的穿着搭配
so I've been posting pictures of my outfits on this site.
我知道现在还赚不了多少钱
I know it's not a huge money-maker right now,
但每当有人点击链接 买我穿的衣服时
but I do get money whenever someone clicks on a link
我就会有收入
and buys something that I wore.
下学期我会去上商务课
I'm gonna take a business class next semester,
希望能帮助我通过现在做的事
which I'm hoping will help me turn all of this
成为一个造型师
into becoming a stylist.
我已经有1200个粉丝了
I have 1,200 followers.
多数是想知道怎样穿衣搭配的女人
Most are women who want to know what to wear.
还有一些想知道我穿什么的男人
Some are men who want to know what I'm wearing,
不过我已经在想办法
But, you know, I'm trying to figure a way
屏蔽那些变态了
to block all of the pervs.
所以 这就是我的规划
So, yeah. I guess that is my plan.
真是太棒了
It's amazing.
我们真为你骄傲
We are so proud of you.
省省吧 你们总是用恶意揣测我
Don't even, guys. You always assume the worst of me.
亲爱的
Honey --
你们两个坐在那儿
No, you guys sit here
假装是我的朋友 却对我评头论足
acting like we're drinking buddies, judging me,
事实是我对未来的规划比你们两个
when I have a better handle on my future
在我这么大时能做到的都要好
than either one of you did at my age.
你曾经想做个魔术师
You? You wanted to be a magician.
而你呢 三分钟就换一次专业
And you were changing your major every three minutes,
这是外公告诉我的
according to grandpa --
顺便说一句
who, by the way,
我和外公一起喝酒好多年了
has been drinking with me for years
因为他爱我
because he loves me,
而且觉得我喝高了的时候说话很风趣
and he thinks I say funny things when I'm buzzed.
很显然 叙利亚局势日趋紧张
Well, apparently, the situation in Syria is worsening.
是啊
I know.
现在联合国有证据显示阿萨德
In fact, now U.N. evidence suggests that Assad was --
你是在照着手机念么
Are you reading this off your phone?
什么
What?!
你在
You're --
不是 没有
No! No! What --
-我只是在确认没有记错细节 -小卡
- I was just making sure my facts were straight... - Cam.
以便我对当今局势高谈阔论
...before I started a spirited conversation of current events.
好吧
Yeah.
还说什么了
What else does it say?
谢谢
Thank you.
不好意思 那是金枪鱼鞑靼吗
Sorry. Is that the tuna tartare?
是啊 很好吃
Yes, and it is delicious.
我应该点那个的
Oh, I should've ordered it.
想尝一口吗
Would you like a taste?
不用了 但是谢谢 你人真好
Oh, no. But thank you. That's very sweet.
她是认真的 卡蒂喜欢跟别人分享食物
She really means it. Uh, Katie loves sharing food.
我也是 我觉得
Me, too. You know, I think
在大家庭里长大都会这样
it's growing up in a big family,
因为晚餐桌上的所有东西
'cause everything at suppertime on the table
都是给大家一起吃的
was up for grabs.
我们不做饭前祷告
We didn't say grace.
我们会说 各就各位 预备 开吃
We said, "On your marks, get set, go."
你的语气跟我爸完全一样
You sound exactly like my dad.
他出生在密苏里一个很大的家庭里
He was from this really big family in Missouri, and --
不是吧
Shut up!
我自己就是个密苏里的乡下孩子
I'm a Missouri farm boy, myself!
-不是吧 -天啊 我叫小卡
- Stop! - Oh, my gosh! I'm Cam.
很高兴认识你 小卡
Well, right pleased to meet you, Cam.
这是布兰登
This is Brandon.
你好 她平常不这样说话的
Hi. She doesn't really talk like that.
他时不时也会有口音
Oh, well, he slips in and out of his accent
就像《泰坦尼克号》里的凯特·温丝莱特
like Kate Winslet in "Titanic."
-我叫米奇尔 -你好
- Uh, I'm Mitchell, by the way. - Hi.
-你好 -你点了什么 布兰登
- Hi. - What -- what's yours, Brandon?
看起来也很好吃
It looks delicious, too.
这是马铃薯干酪松露
It's the truffle parmesan gnocchi.
但是你知道吗 如果你想尝一口那个
Do you know what, though? If you want a bite of that,
你就找错人了
you're barking up the wrong tree.
因为那是一个严格的不分享区
'cause that dish is in a strict no-share zone.
我只是
I just --
不喜欢别人从我的盘子里吃东西
I don't like people eating off my plate.
因为我们不是动物 我也一样
Yeah, because you're not an animal. I'm the same way.
天啊 我们完全一样
Oh, my gosh! You're exactly us!
不 你们要更有趣
No, you guys are more interesting,
因为你们基情四射
'cause you have the whole gay thing.
卡蒂 你都不知道他们是不是
Katie, you don't know if they're gay.
你真可爱
Okay, that's adorable.
是啊 我们的关系很明显
Yeah, it was -- it was a pretty safe bet.
我要去下洗手间
Okay. I'm running to the powder room.
小卡 尝尝这个
Cam, please try the tartare,
一会儿不管你点了什么 我也要尝尝
because whatever you order, I want a taste.
没问题 不过你要快点回来
Okay. Well, don't you dillydally,
因为我一挂上饲料袋就慢不下来
because I ain't exactly slow once I tie on the ol' feed bag!
别激动 亲爱的
Calm down, honey boo boo.
-她真可爱 -超级可爱
- She's so cute! - Very adorable.
布兰登 你是做什么工作的
So, Brandon, what do you do for a living? Are you --
听我说 伙计们 我不想这么没礼貌
Look, guys. I-I hate to be blunt,
但是你们能不能给我们一点空间
but could you please give us some space?
没问题
Not a problem.
不 不是
Look, no -- no, it's --
你们人很好 只是我
I mean, you guys are great. But I'm gonna...
我今晚要向卡蒂求婚
propose to Katie tonight.
而我觉现在有点...
And I'm kind of feeling -- yeah.
什么 在这吗
What?! Here?!
天啊 这太棒了
Oh, my god! That's amazing!
我们几个月前刚刚订婚
We just got engaged a few months ago.
太好了
Great.
所以我们一定会尊重你们的隐私
Yeah, so we will definitely give you your privacy.
-恭喜你 -是啊
- Congratulations. - Absolutely.
祝你好运
Yeah. Good luck.
这样吧 如果你想的话
You know what? If you wanted,
我可以假装在发短信
I could pretend like I'm texting,
然后用手机把整个过程录下来
and I could video the whole thing on my phone.
这样你就能留作纪念了
That way, you'd have it forever.
真的吗 好啊
Really? I mean, that -- yeah.
-那太好了 -你确定吗
- That would be awesome. - A-are you sure?
他很容易过于激动
He gets very, uh, well, excited.
有可能会漏出马脚
And he might give it away.
米奇尔 我觉得凭我对卡蒂的了解
Mitchell, um, I think I know Katie well enough
我能看出她有没有起疑心
to tell if she's getting suspicious.
-小卡 -她说过我可以尝尝的
- Cam?! - She said I could.
见鬼的开瓶器去哪儿了
The hell's the corkscrew?
你想谈谈吗
Do you want to talk about it?
没什么可谈的
There's nothing to talk about!
小短总是做傻事
Shorty does dumb things all the time.
我打赌 不出三个月
You mark my words -- in three months,
他就会花光钱滚回来了
he'll be back here needing money.
也许你不高兴不是因为小短会滚回来
Maybe this is not about Shorty coming back.
而是因为小短可能不会回来了
Maybe this is about Shorty not coming back.
曼尼
Manny.
她的意思是 在你内心深处
What she's saying is, deep down,
害怕小短会爱上哥斯达黎加
you're afraid Shorty's going to love Costa Rica,
你就永远失去自己最好的朋友了
and you'll lose your best friend forever.
你一直都是这样
That's what you do.
你故意疏远别人 这样他们离开时
You push people away, so when they leave,
你就不会那么难受
it doesn't hurt that much.
我搞不明白 你们这代人那么伟大
I don't get it. You're the greatest generation,
怎么就没有情感呢
but why can't you feel?
你怎么不能像其他青春期少年
Why can't you spend your teen years
整天呆在房间不出来呢
locked in your bedroom like a normal kid?
看吧 他现在在疏远我了
See? Now he's doing it to me.
杰 这是你必须面对的
Uh, you have to face it, Jay.
我终有一天会搬出去
One day, I'll be moving out of this house.
你可以写个保证吗
Can I get that in writing?
我脑海里现在都是30岁的你
'cause I just can't shake this image of a 30-year-old you
吃着我的食物 还黏着我老婆
eating my food and cuddling with my wife.
男孩子永远都该黏他们的妈妈
Boys should never stop cuddling their mothers.
我会做噩梦的
I'm gonna have nightmares!
你假装很强硬
You pretend to be so tough.
可你知道我怎么想吗
But you know what I think?
我觉得事实上
I think that deep down,
你才是这屋子里感情最细腻的人
you're the most sensitive person in this house.
看吧
See?
又开始了
You did it again.
一说到这种敏感的话题
I say something that strikes a nerve,
你就受不了了
and immediately, you cannot handle it.
所以你才这样逃避话题
That's why you "Pbht" in my face!
终于发现一个你不那么可爱的地方了
We just found the one thing you can't make sexy.
又来了
There it is again.
我需要喝一杯
I need a drink.
杰 你得跟小短说清楚
Jay, you have to make this right with Shorty.
告诉他你的真实感受
You have to tell him how you feel!
他可是你那么多年的老朋友
He has been a great compadre with you for many years.
除了他还有谁给你的笑话捧场
Besides, who else is going to laugh at your jokes?
大把人欣赏我的笑话
Lots of people laugh at my jokes.
除了你的员工以外还有别人吗
Name one person that doesn't work for you.
要不你们两个还是一边温存去吧
Hey, you know what? Why don't you two just go cuddle?
她来了
Okay, here she comes.
淡定
Stay calm.
-你会露馅的 -你才要淡定
- You're gonna spoil it. - You stay calm.
看起来真不错 这是什么
Ooh, that looks good. What is it?
这个是烤鱿鱼圈
Um, uh, this is the grilled calamari.
很美味的 你要不要来一"环"
It's scrumptious. Would you care for a ring?
我是说你要不要尝一下 亲
I -- um, I mean, dig in there, girlfriend!
不用了 谢谢
Oh, no, that's okay. Thank you.
看起来超美味
This looks so delicious.
我的也很美味
Yeah, mine's delicious, too.
卡蒂
Katie...
你今晚真美
You look so beautiful tonight.
要知道我从来没遇到过像你这么好的人
You know, I-I've never met anyone like you,
我也知道不可能再遇到了
and I know that I never will. And I...
我好爱你
I love you so much.
你能让我变成世界上最幸福的男人吗
Will you make me the happiest man on earth
-嫁给我 -什么
- and be my bride? - What?!
我的天啊
Oh, my god!
-不行 -不行吗
- No! - No?
不行
No!
对不起
Sorry.
你知道这里以前是个银行吗
Did you know that this place used to be a bank?
真的哦
Was it, really?
我只是 我不想结婚 布兰登
I just -- I don't want to be married, Brandon.
我们会变得跟那些
We'll end up like one of those couples
相对无言的夫妻一样
that just sits there with nothing to talk about
直到移情别恋
until we glom on to other people.
我简直不敢相信 你 你不爱我吗
I can't believe this. You -- you don't love me?
-不 -不爱吗
- NO! - NO?
-对不起 -不
- I'm sor... - NO!
我需要透透气
I need some air.
叙利亚那边有什么新情况
So, Syria, any updates?
-还没什么 -没有啊
- No, nothing yet. - Nothing.
你还记得她小时候发不出"p"这个音
Do you remember how cute she was when she was little
-有多可爱吗 -烤"堵"豆
- and she couldn't say her P's? - "BAKE A-TATOES."
烤"堵"豆 还有"饼"果酱
"Bake a-tatoes" and "Attlesauce".
"饼"果酱
"Attlesauce"!
能给我点"饼"果酱吗
"Can I have attlesauce?"
首先 你有点高了
First of all, you're screaming.
我们可以买单了吗 拜托
Can we just get the check, please?
你可以不要生我们的气了吗
Could you please not be mad at us anymore?
我们很抱歉让你有被摆布的感觉
We are very sorry that you felt manipulated.
你们知道我觉得最讽刺的是什么吗
You know what I'm pretty sure is ironic?
你们花那么多时间担心
You guys spend all this time worrying
我将来要做什么
about what I'm going to do,
但也许你们应该开始思考一下
and maybe you should start thinking
你们要做什么了
about what you're going to do.
这是什么意思
What are you talking about?
我们都离开家以后你们打算做什么
Well, what are you gonna do when we're gone?
有什么计划
What's your plan?
-我们会好好的 -是啊
- Uh, to be fine. - Yeah.
-因为我们很好啊 -特别好
- 'cause we're fine. - Totally.
你们都走了
You guys are gone.
我们就买辆休旅车
We get an R.V. Bam!
我 你妈妈
Me, mama...
外加一条狗 默林 踏上旅程
and our dog, Merlin, hit the open road.
不 我可不要把我的晚年
No. I am not spending my golden years
浪费在一个个房车公园里
driving around an R.V. park,
整日寻找地方安营扎寨
looking for a place to plug my house in.
不 我要去周游世界
No. I am gonna go see the world.
那你想去哪里
Where do you wanna go?
我不知道 菲尔 印度 非洲
I don't know, Phil. India. Africa.
痢疾 会得痢疾
Diarrhea. Diarrhea.
看起来你们真的要开始规划一下
Wow. It sounds like you guys really need to start thinking
你们的未来了
about your future.
我们走后你要让默林住在狗舍吗
Are you just gonna put Merlin in a kennel when we're gone?
菲尔 默林根本不存在
Okay, Phil, Merlin doesn't exist.
孩子们走后你为何要
And why do you want to get a dog to take care of
急于找只狗来养呢
so soon after the kids leave?
因为我需要有人疼爱 克莱尔
Well, I'm gonna need someone to love me, Claire.
与此同时 妈妈
And in the meantime, mom,
外公想让你接管公司 但是
grandpa wants you to take over the business, but...
那是你想要的吗
Do you want that?
这么久远的事情我还没想过
I-I guess I hadn't thought this far into the future.
爸爸 你要一直以卖房子为生吗
And, dad, are you just gonna keep selling houses?
我不是想要动摇你的心思
I mean, I don't want to blow your mind here,
但你还是可以成为一个魔术师啊
but you could still be a magician.
我可以
I could.
他不行
He couldn't.
真的吗
Really?
你身后的这个盐罐可不是这么说的
This salt shaker behind your head says different.
菲尔 你把盐弄到我身上了
Oh, Phil, you're getting salt all over me.
我要变成玛格丽特了[想要一杯]
I feel like a Margarita.
-马上来 -不 不 不 不
- You got it! - No, no, no, no, no, no!
结账吧 麻烦了
Just the check, please.
好的
Okay.
非常感谢你
Thank you so much.
-谢了 兄弟 -多谢
- Thanks, buddy. - Yeah.
糟了 我的钱包在另一件外套里
Oh, no. I left my wallet in the other coat.
我没带包包
I did not bring my purse.
没事 我来吧
It's fine, guys. I got this.
-谢谢你宝贝 -谢谢你 亲爱的
- Honey, thank you. - Oh, thank you, sweetie.
-等下看来也要我来开车了吧 -是啊
- I should probably drive, too, huh? - Probably.
-我觉得 也是 -是啊
- I gue-- yeah. - Yeah.
不如我留在这里结账 你们去叫门童
Why don't you guys have the valet pull the car up
把车取来
while I pay the check?
这倒是可以
That we can do.
伙计们 那边
Uh, you guys, it's that way.
-是吧 -是啊
- Mm-hmm. - It is.
顺便说一下 我们其实有很多可聊的
Y-you know, for the record, we do have a lot to talk about.
今天只是把有些话题先放一放
Yeah, we just took a couple of topics off the table
因为我们今晚想来一次浪漫的约会
because we wanted to have a romantic date night.
也许我们太想让今晚特别一点了
And it probably put too much pressure on it to be special,
事实上我和他在一起的每一天都很特别
but the truth is, every day I spend with this man is special.
小卡
Oh, Cam!
不 我才是幸运的那个人
Oh, no, I'm the lucky one.
我们都是
There we are.
抱歉
I'm sorry.
我想刚才布兰登求婚时我只是慌乱了
I guess I just panicked when Brandon asked me.
我们很不一样 我知道这看来
I mean, we're so different. And I know it seems petty,
很矫情 但其实不然
but it speaks to something bigger.
我不知道我能否与一个
I don't know if I can spend the rest of my life
不让我碰他食物的人共度余生
with the kind of guy who won't let me eat off his plate.
相信我 那不是问题
Trust me -- it can be done.
我也不应该太在乎这件事
And I should not make such a big deal about that.
我保证会努力调整的
I promise I'll try and do better.
不 你说得对 你不喜欢我那样
No, you're right. You don't like it,
我就应该尊重你的喜好
and I should respect that more.
你们结婚了吗
Are you guys married?
今年五月结
Oh, this May.
-但我们算是结婚很多年了 -是的
- But, basically, we've been married for years. - Yeah.
小卡难道就是我心中的完美人选吗
I-I mean, is Cam everything that I dreamed of?
谨言慎行 律师
Tread lightly, counselor.
是的 他就是
Yes. Yes, he is.
因为尽管经历了种种妥协
Because through all the compromises
协商与争执
and negotiations and arguments
甚至是厌倦情绪
and sometimes even boredom,
我无法想象没有他的生活
I cannot picture my life without him.
说得真好
That's very sweet.
但要是我就不会说厌倦 不过
I would've scooted past the boredom, but...
说到最后 卡蒂 你必须问问你自己
At the end of the day, Katie, you have to ask yourself,
你能想象没有这个人的生活吗
can you imagine your life without this person?
好了
Hey. All right, look.
我买完单了 我们走吧
I, uh, paid the check, okay? Let's just go.
布兰登 你能先坐下吗
Brandon, can you just please sit?
我一直在和他们两个聊
I've been talking to the guys here,
他们真的让我想了很多
and they really opened my eyes.
真的吗
They did?
是的
Yes.
我尝试着想象没有你的生活
I've been trying to picture my life without you, and...
你知道吗
You know what?
我能接受
I can.
我们可没那么说
We didn't tell her that.
我没那么说
I didn't say that.
不 我想和你们一样 懂吗
No, I want what you guys have, okay?
抱歉 布兰登
I'm sorry, Brandon.
对不起 但我们都该有那样的感情
I am so sorry, but we both deserve that.
我从未如此确定过
I've never been so sure of anything.
好了 我还是
You know what? I'm just...
打车回去好了
gonna go get a cab, okay?
再见
Goodbye.
谢谢
And thank you.
-别 别谢我们 -我们什么都没做
- Don't-- don't thank us! - We didn't do anything,
我们真的没有
So... we didn't, honestly.
这真是我人生最悲剧的一晚
This is the worst night of my life.
抱歉
I'm sorry.
但是好在一切都结束了
But, I mean, um, a-at least now it's over.
你可以开始新生活了
You can... start to move on.
我尝试着想象没有你的生活
I've been trying to picture my life without you.
你知道吗
And you know what?
-傻缺手机 -我能接受
- S-stupid phone. - I can.
这手机着魔了
It's a... devil phone.
米奇尔出生时 早产了一个月
When Mitchell was born, he was a month premature.
当时事态很紧急
So it was touch and go there for a while.
是凌晨两点
It's 2 a.m.
我走进医院的等候室想喘口气
I walk out into the hospital waiting room to get some air,
小短也在
and there's Shorty.
他在那坐了六个小时了
He'd been sitting there for six hours
还坚持要继续再呆两天
and refused to leave for the next two days.
米奇尔的中间名就是这么来的
That's where we got Mitchell's middle name.
不是叫小短
Not Shorty --
是文森特
Vincent.
M.V.P[最有价值球员]
"M.V.P."
这点上我们也有些不成熟
We were a little premature on that one, too.
歌洛莉亚 我要开车出去了
Gloria, I'm going for a drive!
替我向小短问好
Say hi to Shorty for me!
没跟你说话
I'm not talking to you!
我正要去找你
I was just coming to see you.
我把外套落在这里了
Um, I left my jacket.
在这呢 进来吧
Oh! There it is! Come on in.
小短 你知道我说的那些话
Uh, Shorty, you know that stuff I said, uh --
-我懂 -我们没事吧
- Yeah, I get it. - We're good, huh?
没事
Under the bridge.
好的 回头见
All right. I'll see you.
小短 等等
Shorty, wait.
我有话想跟你说
I need to say something to you.
说吧
Yeah.
我想说谢谢你
I want to thank you...
感谢我们一同经历的好时光
for all the great times we've had.
是啊 我们
Yeah. We, um...
-我们有过很多快乐时光 -是啊
- We had a lot of laughs. - Yeah.
你应该知道
And you should know that, uh...
你是我最好的朋友
you're my best friend.
知道吗
You know?
也许是我一生中最好的朋友
Probably the best friend I'm ever gonna have.
杰 你这是干什么
Jay, I mean... what are you doing to me?
这对我有点难 我只是
This is hard for me. I'm just...
我只是想告诉你我的感受
I'm just trying to tell you how I feel.
那我也告诉你我的感受
Well, I'm gonna tell you how I feel.
我真崇拜你 杰
I admire the hell out of you, Jay.
我总跟达琳说 "这是个真男人"
I always tell Darlene, "That's a real guy."
自立 敢说敢干
Self-made, stand-up,
是那种你愿意和他在同一战壕奋斗的人
the kind of guy you want to be in a foxhole with.
我没那么好
Well, I'm not all that.
我也没下过战壕
Well, it's not like I've been in a foxhole.
我会想你的 文森特
I'm gonna miss you, Vincent.
我也会想你的
I'm gonna miss you, too.
我爱你
I love you.
我也爱你 小杰杰
I love you, too, Jay bird.
真的非常爱
I really, really do.
给我打电话 好吗
You call me, okay?
每天都打
Every day.
每一天
Every damn day.
说实话
If I'm being honest,
我没想到场面会这么娘
this is a little girlier than I thought.
两年
Two years.
她怎么就这么走了
How could she just walk away?
-知道吗 她这是帮了你 -绝对的
- You know what? She did you a favor. - Absolutely.
-你能找到更好的 -好上百倍的
- You can do so much better. - Oh, my god. Insanely better.
他没开玩笑 布兰登 你这么帅
No, he's not kidding. Brandon, you are seriously gorge!
要我说 她和你在一起绝对是占便宜了
If you ask me, she got the better end of the deal.
你们真这么觉得吗
You really think so?
-是啊是啊 -是啊
- Yes! Yes! - Yes!
还有她那头假金发 我不确定
And her whole fake blond thing? I don't know.
-有点不太正经 -而且说实话
- It was kind of trampy. - And truth be told,
她看起来不是很阳光
she didn't seem that bright.
她是不是比你大
And is she older than you?
-她看起来比你大多了 -相信我们
- Because she looked significantly older than you. - Trust us.
这是发生在你身上的最好的事了
This is the best thing that's ever happened to you.
这辈子发生的最好的事
Best thing that's ever happened to you.
谢天谢地 你还在
Oh! Thank god you're still here!
刚刚在回家的路上 突然我就哭了
I was on my way home, and all of a sudden, I started crying.
我意识到我刚刚只是被吓到了
And I realized I was just scared.
我爱你 我真的很抱歉
And I love you. And I'm so, so sorry.
我愿意 布兰登 如果你还愿意娶我
And, yes, Brandon, if you'll still have me,
我愿意 我要嫁给你
Yes, I will marry you!
-认识你们很高兴 -走吧
- So nice meeting you. - Okay.